<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[the Ephemeral Me]]></title>
  <link href="http://ephemeral.me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ephemeral.me/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-16T12:26:29+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ephemeral.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[At the door to a new beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/05/09/at-the-door-to-a-new-beginning/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-09T18:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/05/09/at-the-door-to-a-new-beginning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since too many memories are clogging my mind, this is not a well thought out
piece about parting and graduating, this is just a compilation of thoughts that
came about during the last few days.</p>

<p>What began as the fruit of some hard work and extreme luck, what came after a
choice that decided the direction of my life (between medical or engineering -
that&#8217;s all that&#8217;s available for a middle class average student), what started
with me as a dumb, innocent and childish teenager, is now coming to an end. As
it ends, I contemplate. The several dimensions of life here have left a trove
of memories.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, food, yes. Food didn&#8217;t come easily. We struggled to feed ourselves.
Several things saved us by providing the occasional-slowly-turned-regular
respite from the mess food.  The grand dinners in the mess, the big fat slices
of Ideals from 3rd/5th blocks, the sunday Masala Dosas, the gobi manchurians,
the kheers, the rasnas and the paneer items. The (pseudo-)veg food from GNPD,
the variety of alu paranthas from the NC, GBNC, GNPD and GPD, the lassi at
Bittus, the lingering after-taste of pani puri after a satisfying streak of
chats at Kailash, the cheap milkshakes at the cold house, the staring sulky
I&#8217;ll-take-you-for-granted waiter at Suraj, the funny proprietor of SD (and NC
(and the supplier at every meeting/seminar with free food)), the teetotaller&#8217;s
gang eating fried rice at RR, the (pseudo-)unlimited buffets in Mangalore, the
holy shrine called Pabbas, the weirdest remixed and still home-like food from
Ram Bhavan, the mirage called Kebab Studio, the unexplored Froth on Top. So
while the messes happily served humongous amounts of undercooked rice, the
tasteless sambar-rasams, the painfully limited good sabzis and bulletproof
rotis, awful breakfasts and extremely light evening snacks, nobody cared.</p>

<p>Travel proved to be the best drug. Treks to KP, Bandaje, numerous waterfalls
around South Canara in the obscurity of western ghats, bus trips to nearly every
tourist place, the insanely fast bike trip to Yana and the best ever beach trip
to Gokarna. The getting lost at Bandaje, the missing train in Goa, the shivering
cold of west-India and the bloody rain in KP. The unparalleled flatness of the
Rann of Kutch, the remnants in the wilderness of Dholavira and the single
majestic hill that stood in the middle of hundreds of kilometers of chest-deep
saline water. The Sawai Gandharv and the Yamini. The food at Mysore&#8217;s homes, the
lovely nostalgic lazy times in Goa&#8217;s home. The duo&#8217;s wandering to Bekal and
wading the tides to reach Sasihitlu. The bathing in dirty backwaters at Pavanje,
the journey on the side of the engine of a goods train through rainy hills to
Doodhsagar, the exploring of Chennai and the fairs of Mangalore.  The
accompanying artists to schools and attending Conventions.  Travel was that
boost that would push us through semesters. Travel recharged our batteries as it
drained our physiques and filled us with memories.</p>

<p>Friends fill as much the NITK life as water does a watermelon. Friends will
constitute all the memories that define college life. When it is a hostel with
not a very easy life, the bond multiplies in strength. With assignments and
projects, scorching heat and incessant rains, block timings and warden whining,
bad food and no water, surprise tests and relative grading, we found several
reasons to bond. The thought of missing my friends frightens me.</p>

<p>I made all kinds of friends. The irritatingly nerdy kind, the elite sarcastic
kind, the studious kind, the shy kind, the hardworking kind, the algorithm
master kind, the silent yet scholarly kind, the chatter-y kind, the NID kind,
the half naked around the varandah kind, the artistic kind, the matching
wavelength partner-in-crime kind, the laughing rampage kind, the ladiesman kind,
the directory-of-every-girl kind, the deceitful kind, the loving kind, the idol
kind, the adventurous kind, the leader kind, the silent kind, the overly caring
kind, the rude rowdy kind, the methodic perfectionist kind and so many more.
Much to my surprise, I have realized  every one of the friendships is worth
treasuring. I will.</p>

<p>NITK has given me several things that are unique and bring a rush of feelings
every time I remember them. The beautiful beach, the unforgiving rains, the
villages around the campus, the unpredictable whether and towering lighthouse.
Taking late evening strolls to the beach, early morning excursions on the
railroad to reach Pavanje, getting on the terrace to watch the clouds build up
while the lighthouse&#8217;s beam searched the edges of the horizon, passionately
shouting in TV room and breaking furniture and shouting for and against teams,
standing up with pride as India grabbed another world cup &#8220;for Sachin&#8221;, the
parting of couples at 9:55, the follow-me-everywhere Snowy and the endless
headbanging nights of Incident. The thursday evenings, the precious times with
artists and the concerts by the greats.</p>

<p>The fun-filled and sometimes irritating eerie joblessness spanned our schedules
like ether, dominating everything else, causing me to sometimes doubt the
purpose of last 4 years. When I look back, I feel guilty sometimes.  The most
prominent of all guilts that plague my mind is serious: I didn&#8217;t learn anything.
Yes. In the four years, 192 credits, hundreds of gruelling examinations and
assignments and project (reports), I have learnt nearly nothing. Academics was
full of compromises, last minute slog, lies, curses and incessant demands for
&#8220;research and publication&#8221;. I came in to become an engineer. My curriculum
focussed on anything but that. Teachers demanded research-y projects, indented,
numbered, abstract-litreature survey-result-future work-references-ified
reports, overnight submission to conferences, copied assignments, pointless
examinations and 75% attendances. They came in to class to teach subjects in a
way that made me cringe innumerable times. We doodled, whatsapped, Gangnam
danced, dozed, ate, played and ogled in class. Labs, though, were marginally
better, where I felt I was learning. Projects started with outlandish demands
right from the beginning, and never ended. Placing a random number generator
function with a probability of 74% and claiming a 74% result hurt my confidence
more than I thought it would. (Oh and dont please get me started about corruption
and inefficient administration and equal measure of indifference among students
and administration.)</p>

<p>While the conclusion that education is secondary came right in the beginnings, I
looked around for what else I could absorb from this cauldron of talent and
diversity. It would be the greatest mistake to not learn anything after living
as one among such a diverse talented set of people. And so I did, and did well
in retrospect.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s all coming to an end. Now all that lies ahead of us is a future - one
that&#8217;s full of opportunities along with confusion, one that holds as many doubts
as hopes. I dont know what&#8217;s in it for me, but right now I dont have many
regrets.</p>

<p>The no-due certificate that I hold in my hands now seems silly. I know I can
never pay back everything that I owe to NITK.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The need for control]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/04/30/the-need-for-control/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-30T14:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/04/30/the-need-for-control</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>With more than 20 hours between the exam that just got over and the last exam I
will take before graduating, I was spending time on HackerNews and Reddit as
usual. And then I come across <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yXEuEUQIP3Q">this video</a> of one Mister Fred Rogers on the
internet.  There is a children&#8217;s poem that he recites, which moved me like nothing
I remember from recent times:</p>

<blockquote><p>What do you do with the mad that you feel<br/>
When you feel so mad you could bite? <br/>
When the whole wide world feels oh, so wrong <br/>
And nothing you do seems very right? <br/>
<!-- more --> <br/>
What do you do? Do you punch your bag?  <br/>
Do you pound some clay or some dough? <br/>
Do you round up friends for a game of tag <br/>
And see how fast you go?</p>

<p>Its great to be able to stop <br/>
when you plan the thing that&#8217;s wrong, <br/>
And be able to do something else instead  <br/>
And think this song:</p>

<p>I can stop when I want to, can stop when I wish, <br/>
can stop stop stop any time. <br/>
And what a good feeling to feel like this <br/>
And know that the feeling is really mine. <br/>
Know that there is something deep inside <br/>
That helps us become what we can.</p>

<p>For a girl can be some day a woman, <br/>
And a boy can be some day a man.</p></blockquote>

<p><a href="http://pbskids.org/rogers/songLyricsWhatDoYouDo.html">(Official lyrics and many other poems for children)</a></p>

<p><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fred_Rogers">Mister Fred Rogers</a> is asked to defend the $20mn that was granted by the US
Govt. for his children&#8217;s education programme, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mister_Rogers%27_Neighborhood">Mister Rogers&#8217; Neighborhood</a>.
In the hearing, he is talking to an authoritative man who has the chair for the
hearing. With his soothing polite voice and utterly humble way of speaking,
Mister Rogers asks if he could read out a poem that he wrote to give an idea of
what his programme gives the children. The man on the seat says of course, and
Mister Rogers goes on to read this poem.</p>

<p>How profound, meaningful and touching the lines are, is substantiated by the
chair&#8217;s reaction: he exclaims &#8220;I think it&#8217;s wonderful. I think you&#8217;ve just
earned yourself a twenty million dollars!&#8221;</p>

<p>I wish I had listened to these lines when I was a child. Maybe then, just maybe,
I&#8217;d not have said some words and done some deeds that now I want to forget
about.</p>

<hr />

<p>PS: With the amount of people that interact, forums such as these stand out
among the other &#8220;Social Networks&#8221; that I otherwise participate in.  Yeah,
Facebook, I&#8217;m looking at you. (Even twitter has people from all over the world,
but it&#8217;s just that finding good stuff on twitter is just too much hard work.)
What I really like about HN or Reddit are the people and stuff that I discover
that absolutely blow my mind. Mister Rogers and his story is one such thing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A CSI in Surathkal]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/02/05/a-csi-in-surathkal/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-05T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/02/05/a-csi-in-surathkal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That afternoon, we were waiting in our project guide&#8217;s room for my teammate to
arrive.  He came 5 minutes late as usual but this time he had the weirdest
excuse to give. Not so much an excuse, what he said made me forget that he was
actually late - &#8220;there&#8217;s a murdered body in front of the department!&#8221;.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p> Shocked as I should be, I looked out of the transparent wall panes
of the front of the department. These panes line the entire length of the front
side of the building. It&#8217;s a useless ornament pretty much, an exception being
the nice panoramic view that it provides of the old East Side campus.  This time
it wasn&#8217;t so nice, for an ominous crowd was already gathering around a spot on
the side of the highway. Several thoughts crossed my mind
- &#8220;Could it be a student? A teacher? Natural death?  Accident on the highway?
  Animal body?&#8221;. From fourth floor, nothing was clear.</p>

<p>I gave a heads up to my guide about the happenings before we sat down to discuss
the project and he replied &#8220;It&#8217;s all a part of life. Come in, let us continue&#8221;.
We sat down for an hour or so and when we came out, I had an overwhelming desire
to just be down there at the scene to watch the proceedings. The Wire, one of
the best TV shows of all time, has got me hooked to crime scenes and police
work. So I thought I&#8217;d catch a bite of it in real life.</p>

<p>My excitement was slightly dampened when I caught the first glimpse of the scene
- mind you, this was about an hour after the murder. There was no cordoned-off
crime scene. No vehicles with beacons (hey, the politicians need them beacons
to parade around, how can they be spared for silly crime work?). No forensic
experts sweeping for DNA and fingerprints and hair samples, no nothing. There
were a couple of police men staring at this and that, whistling at the
occasional bus that stopped at the bus-stop. There were people, both standing
around and in the buses, staring at the small patch of blood on the ground
&#8216;cordoned off&#8217; using 2 road-blocks from NITK. The most serious looking man in
the scene was the head of Watch at NITK, in his khakhi uniform.</p>

<p>I left the scene soon, because there were only photographers taking photos of
blood and people creating rumors. Before I left, I met the police guy and
asked him, &#8220;What happened?&#8221;. He said, &#8220;Murder&#8221;. Of course.</p>

<p>After chilling out for half an hour in the nearby Amul shop, I came by again
to see what had developed. Hey, there were a couple of police now with gloves
on. Wow, I thought, CSI! The one with the more serious uniform walked around,
searching for something. Hair? Nah, he&#8217;s not getting any, other than some from
the heads of soon-balding guys like me around the crime scene. Murder weapon?
Maybe. But after an hour and half, now I thought it should be a miracle to
find anything useful in a crime scene thronged by civilians.</p>

<p>He bent down and picked up something from the gutter with his gloved hand. A
plastic cover that someone had dumped as waste. Then he came back to crime
scene, and picked up a juice carton that was crushed by a hundred footsteps.
How were they evidences, I still wondered, for they looked like all the other
garbage in our campus. Now he bent down near the blood. As I realized what he
was doing, my mind went numb. He scooped up the bloody mud with the carton,
and put it into the cover from the dump. Carefully, he filled 3 more covers
from the dump with the mud from the crime scene. Then he put them all in
another big cover that his assistant had painstakingly collected from the
dump, then hung it all on the handlebar of his white police Pulsar, took off
his gloves, drove away. CSI done.</p>

<p>Life was back on track as I hurried to SJA to set up stage for the Hindustani
Shehnai concert that was going to start in an hour. As I went about the
arrangements, a friend showed me a photo on her phone which she said was going
viral on WhatsApp. It was a close-up photo of a body lying in foetal position
on ground. His guts were spilled out, right arm cut, fingers scattered, head
bludgeoned and was clearly dead.</p>

<p><figure class="img cap-top"><img src="http://ephemeral.me/images/nsfw-murder-pixelated.jpg" title="(NSFW) Photo on WhatsApp" ><figcaption class="imgcaption">(NSFW) Photo on WhatsApp</figcaption></figure></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First day at Intuit]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/14/first-day-at-intuit/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T14:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/14/first-day-at-intuit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Le me dozing off in Intuit office - jobless on the first day - on my comfortable
SteelCase chair.</p>

<p>&#8220;Hey, Wake up!&#8221;</p>

<p>I&#8217;m up. It&#8217;s my mentor Harsh Vardhan Gupta. He has a serious look on his face, and his phone in his hand.</p>

<p>&#8220;The team manager is back from the US. He tried to wake you up, but you wouldn&#8217;t respond. He called me.&#8221;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I took a few more moments, still sleepy after the heavy lunch.</p>

<p>&#8220;He just came in. He wanted to see you, but he found you sleeping with Facebook open on your
screen. He&#8217;s pissed off!&#8221;</p>

<p>I slowly realized the gravity of the situation. I just screwed up my first meeting with my team manager. I probably even screwed up my
chances with Intuit.</p>

<p>&#8220;What? Did he come in? He saw me sleeping?&#8221;, I asked, rubbing my eyes.</p>

<p>&#8220;Yes, he tried to wake you up. He&#8217;s off for a meeting now. He asked me to send him your phone number.&#8221;, he said, and in a hurry took down my
number on his mobile.</p>

<p>&#8220;Alright, he&#8217;s angry, so probably you should see him as soon as he&#8217;s back!&#8221;</p>

<p>The colleagues voiced their concern, too. &#8220;Harsh, you meet
the manager first!&#8221;, &#8220;Siddhartha, go apologize!&#8221;, &#8220;He&#8217;s not that bad either, he
might forgive you..&#8221;, they said. Nothing helped the mood.</p>

<p>I washed my face. Tried to do something work-related, but was just plain worried. I
was imagining the manager, and was nervous like shit.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>Then the whole office burst out into laughter, and they come and pat my back and
apologize.</p>

<p>The manager is still in the US. Intuit doesn&#8217;t care if we sleep during work,
heck, they even have a sleeping room. Intuit has begun well indeed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh! The places you'll go]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/01/oh-the-places-youll-go/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/01/oh-the-places-youll-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a beautiful poem I found from the movie Fracture. It&#8217;s written
by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oh,_the_Places_You'll_Go!">Dr. Seuss</a>. It&#8217;s inspiring!</p>

<blockquote><p>Congratulations!<br/>
Today is your day,<br/>
You&#8217;re off to Great Places!<br/>
You&#8217;re off and away!</p>

<p>You have brains in your head.<br/>
You have feet in your shoes.<br/>
You can steer yourself<br/>
any direction you choose.<br/>
You&#8217;re on your own. And you know what you know.<br/>
And YOU are the guy who&#8217;ll decide where to go.<br/>
<!-- more -->
You&#8217;ll look up and down streets. Look &#8216;em over with care.<br/>
About some you will say, &#8220;I don&#8217;t choose to go there.&#8221;<br/>
With your head full of brains, and your shoes full of feet,<br/>
you&#8217;re too smart to go down any not-so-good street.</p>

<p>And you may not find any<br/>
you&#8217;ll want to go down.<br/>
In that case, of course,<br/>
you&#8217;ll head straight out of town.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s opener there<br/>
in the wide open air.</p>

<p>Out there things can happen<br/>
and frequently do <br/>
to people as brainy<br/>
and footsy as you.</p>

<p>And when things start to happen,<br/>
don&#8217;t worry. Don&#8217;t stew.<br/>
Just go right along.<br/>
You&#8217;ll start happening too.</p>

<p>OH!<br/>
THE PLACES YOU&#8217;LL GO!</p>

<p>You&#8217;ll be on your way up!<br/>
You&#8217;ll be seeing great sites! <br/>
You&#8217;ll join the high fliers!<br/>
who soar to high heights.</p>

<p>You won&#8217;t lag behind, because you&#8217;ll have the speed.<br/>
You&#8217;ll pass the whole gang and you&#8217;ll soon take the lead.<br/>
Wherever you fly, you&#8217;ll be best of the best.<br/>
Wherever you go, you will top all the rest.</p>

<p>Except when you don&#8217;t.<br/>
Because, sometimes, you won&#8217;t.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m sorry to says so<br/>
but, sadly, it&#8217;s true<br/>
that Bang-ups<br/>
and Hang-ups<br/>
can happen to you</p>

<p>You can get all hung up<br/>
in a prickle-ly perch.<br/>
And your gang will fly on.<br/>
You&#8217;ll be left in a Lurch.</p>

<p>You&#8217;ll come down from the Lunch<br/>
wuth an unpleasant bump.<br/>
And the chances are, then,<br/>
that you&#8217;ll be in a Slump.</p>

<p>And when you&#8217;re in a Slump,<br/>
you&#8217;re not in for much fun.<br/>
Un-slumping yourself <br/>
is not easily done.</p>

<p>You will come to a place where the streets are not marked.<br/>
Some windows are lighted. But mostly they&#8217;re dark.<br/>
A place that could sprain both elbow and chin!<br/>
Do you dare to stay out? Do you dare to go in?<br/>
How much can you lose? How much can you win?</p>

<p>And IF you should go in,should you turn left or right&#8230;<br/>
or right-and-three-quaters? Or maybe not quite?<br/>
Or go around and back and sneak from behind?<br/>
Simple it&#8217;s not, I&#8217;m afraid you will find,<br/>
for a mind-maker-upper to make up his mind.</p>

<p>You can get so confused <br/>
that you&#8217;ll start in to race<br/>
down long and wiggled roads at a break-necking pace<br/>
and grind on for miles across weirdish wild space,<br/>
headed, I fear, toward a most usless place</p>

<p>The Waiting Place&#8230;</p>

<p>&#8230;for people just waiting.</p>

<p>Waiting for a train to go<br/>
or a bus to come, or a plane to go<br/>
or the mail to come, or the rain to go<br/>
or the phone to ring, or the snow to snow<br/>
or waiting around for a Yes or a No<br/>
or waiting for their hair to grow.<br/>
Everyone is just waiting.</p>

<p>Waiting for the fish to bite<br/>
or waiting for wind to fly a kite<br/>
or waiting around for Friday night<br/>
or waiting, perhaps, for their uncle Jake<br/>
or a pot to boil, or a Better Break<br/>
or a string of pearls, or a pair of pants<br/>
or a wig with curls, or Another Chance.<br/>
Everyone is just waiting.</p>

<p>NO!<br/>
That&#8217;s not for you!</p>

<p>Somehow you&#8217;ll escape<br/>
all that waiting and staying.<br/>
You&#8217;ll find the bright places<br/>
where boom bands are playing.</p>

<p>Oh, the places you&#8217;ll go! There is fun to be done!<br/>
There are points to be scored. There are games to be won.<br/>
And the magical things you can do with that ball<br/>
will make you the winning-est winner of all.<br/>
Fame! You&#8217;ll be famous as famous can be,<br/>
with the whole wide world watching you win on TV.</p>

<p>Except when they don&#8217;t.<br/>
Because, sometimes, they won&#8217;t.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m afraid that some times<br/>
you&#8217;ll play lonely games too.<br/>
Games you can&#8217;t win<br/>
&#8216;cause you&#8217;ll play against you.</p>

<p>All Alone!<br/>
Whether you like it or not.<br/>
Alone will be something<br/>
you&#8217;ll be quite a lot.</p>

<p>And when you&#8217;re alone, theres a very good chance<br/>
you&#8217;ll meet things that scare you right out of your pants.<br/>
There are some, down the road between hither and yon,<br/>
that can scare you so much you won&#8217;t want to go on.</p>

<p>But on you will go<br/>
though the whether be foul.<br/>
On you will go<br/>
though your enemies prowl.<br/>
On you will go<br/>
though the Hakken-Kraks howl.<br/>
Onward up many<br/>
a frightening creek,<br/>
though you arms may get sore<br/>
and your sneakers may leak.</p>

<p>On and on you will hike.<br/>
And I know you&#8217;ll hike far<br/>
and face up to your problems<br/>
whatever they are.</p>

<p>You&#8217;ll get mixed up of course,<br/>
as you already know.<br/>
You&#8217;ll get mixed up<br/>
with many stray birds as you go.<br/>
So be sure when you step.<br/>
Step with care and great tact<br/>
and remember that Life&#8217;s<br/>
a Great Balancing Act.<br/>
Just never forget to be dexterous and deft.<br/>
And never mix up your right foot with you left.</p>

<p>And will you succeed?<br/>
Yes! You will indeed!<br/>
(98 and 3/4 percent garanteed!)</p>

<p>KID YOU&#8217;LL MOVE MOUNTAINS!</p>

<p>So&#8230;<br/>
be your name Buxbaum or Bixby or Bray<br/>
or Mordecai Ali Van Alenn O&#8217;Shea<br/>
you&#8217;re off to Great Places!<br/>
Today is your day!<br/>
Your mountain is waiting.<br/>
So&#8230; get on your way!</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[on parting]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/04/30/on-parting/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T13:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/04/30/on-parting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s not often that you end up with a circle of friends that become a part of
you. You wont know it until it&#8217;s time to bid adieu, as with all other things.
But once you realize it, you hope that, you know, time stops. Just one more
outing, one more trek, one more day of fun. Until that inevitable separation
comes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It&#8217;s only getting worse as we are growing older, and world is getting smaller.
By separating I don&#8217;t mean that we are no longer going to the same school but
living in the same town, as it was with our childhood friends. This time, we
came from far off places, and we are going even further. Chances are, we are not
going to meet for a long time.</p>

<p>Is it going to matter? I told myself that we are going to find new friends,
visit new places and hang out with new circles until one day, soon enough, we&#8217;d
stop missing the old <em>junta</em>. It&#8217;s only the fear now, but it&#8217;ll be better in
future, I assured myself. &#8220;Hey, it&#8217;s nice to change, who knows, it might all be
for good.. Chill.. &#8220;, I assured Raja who was apprehensive about the same
thing.</p>

<p>One thing is for sure. Times are not going to be as sweet as they were during
the past couple of years. Neither are we going to be adolescent and in college
again, or are we going to have a company as fine as this. Come what may, nothing
can parallel the world we shared, the moments we spent laughing, eating or
strolling together. The <em>pani-puri</em> will carry the memories with each bite, as
will every outing in future.</p>

<p>That dream, of coming together some day, going on a trip to Europe and
participating in <em>La Tomatino</em> like in one of those movies is already forming.
Hell, even a proposal of buying a custom-made bus and roaming the country is already
being proposed by Raja. It should sound easy, take  a weekend off, meet up and have fun.
How difficult can it be to do that? Future remains to be seen.</p>

<blockquote><p>Ya&#8217;ll will go away, <br/>
some across seas, <br/>
some to universities, <br/>
and some to work, <br/>
but away it is.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s no end to hoping this would never end.<br/>
On the road ahead, see you around the bend!</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying to get scammed.]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/03/09/finally-i-want-to-get-scammed/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-09T00:48:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/03/09/finally-i-want-to-get-scammed</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After reading a couple of times about how people got scammed by popular emails,
like &#8220;I would like you to have my money until I can find a safe passage from moon
back to earth&#8221;, I tried to become a part of one and see how this one pans out.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I got this mail yesterday from, interestingly, a Sgt. Vladir Vicente - that&#8217;s
not even a real name from what I know. The mail had the usual content -</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear,</p>

<p>I am Sgt. Valdir Vicente (3RD INFANTRY DIVISION). I am an American soldier
with British background, serving in the military with the army?s 3rd
infantry division. With a very desperate need for assistance, I have
summed up courage to contact you. I found your contact particulars in an
address journal of a carieer builders database.</p>

<p>I am seeking your kind
assistance to move the sum of $6Millions US Dollars] to you, as far
as I can be assured that my share will be safe in your care until I and my
partner come to you , this is no stolen money, and there are no danger
involved.</p>

<p>My partner and I need a good and reliable person, we can trust to
actualize this dream. The money is from oil proceeds and its legit. We
intend moving it by diplomatic means to you or to a safe and secured
location of your choice. Once the funds get to you,</p>

<p>Please take your 30% out and keep our own 70%.
I shall however leave out other details of this transaction until I
receive an
affirmation of your desire to participate. Please contact me on my
personal email address below for more details.</p>

<p>For more details please visit
http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/middle_east/2988455.stm</p>

<p>Yours truly
Sgt Vladir Vicente
<email></p></blockquote>

<p>Now this I came across while I was cleaning out my spam folder, and I instantly
felt like replying to this. I was trying and clicking out humorous spams like
&#8220;siddhartha, study at Phoenix university and expand your career opportunities&#8221;,
but all of them routinely lead to the same surveys or fake click-counters.</p>

<p>This one, this could be a live person on the other side. Like those somalian/
nigerian criminals. So I replied to this mail:</p>

<blockquote><p>Sir,</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll be glad to help you out.</p>

<p>Please tell me what I have to do next.</p>

<p>Regards,
Siddhartha.</p></blockquote>

<p>So I&#8217;m just waiting for his reply.</p>

<h3>Update - Sat Mar 09, 23:31</h3>

<p>And I get a reply from this man, I think he&#8217;s a genuine scamster anyway. It&#8217;s fun,
and I cant think of any legal/moral implications of this yet, since I&#8217;m publicly
announcing that I&#8217;m going to do this for experimental purpose only and I don&#8217;t
really have the mood to get scammed.</p>

<p>This man here, he is clever. He gives me an option to go to Malaysia from my
country, India, OR get the money straight into the account. Some level of marketing
this is.</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear,</p>

<p>Thanks for your response to my mail.
I will like you to travel to Malaysia where the money is currently deposited with a Diplomatic Finance Vault. Or i will instruct the vault company to deliver the consignment directly to you in your Country.
We will like to invest some part of the money in partnership with you.</p>

<p>My partner is currently serving in Afghanistan while i&#8217;m undergoing treatment here in UK.
So we need your assistance to claim his money.
I need to know if you can be able to travel to Malaysia or if you wish to receive the money in your account.</p>

<p>Waiting for your prompt response.</p>

<p>Best regards,
Valdir Vicente.</p></blockquote>

<p>So that&#8217;s funny. I mean, he actually uses a bait - gives me a bad option and a
GOOD offer. Well, I take the bait.</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear Valdir,</p>

<p>It is very difficult for me to travel to Malaysia, on such short notice. Although, I would take the pain for a devout soldier like you. But It&#8217;ll be great if you can arrange for the money to be transferred to my account here.</p>

<p>I hope I am not troubling your already injured state. I hope you get alright soon.</p>

<p>Send me pictures of afghanistan and UK!</p>

<p>Regards,</p>

<p>Siddhartha</p></blockquote>

<p>I know, it&#8217;s a little bit dramatic, but I want to make sure he thinks I really
fell for him. So now I&#8217;m to wait for some more time.</p>

<p>Good night!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not a college, it's a society]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/01/14/not-a-college/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-14T22:27:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/01/14/not-a-college</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, like many other days, was eventful, joyous, memorable. As I decided to
return to bed for an early start to tomorrow, this thought crossed my mind. Our
college, like many other great institutions, is a society in itself. Not just a
school where students come and study, but a full-fledged society.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I was speaking to my parents on phone. I told them I had flown a kite and eaten
homemade food brought by Vatsa for Sankranti, a festival celebrated today
(about which I know surprisingly little, I&#8217;ll write when I find out). Then I
realized that if I my life had taken a different turn, I would never experience
all that I am now. I suddenly wanted to express this feeling - even though I&#8217;ve
told this to many friends, I want to write about it again.</p>

<p>So I was put into this hostel when I was 12. Like any other child, I probably
imagined the place to be bad, lonely and frightening. I don&#8217;t remember. I
couldn&#8217;t fit in easily, since everyone here was new. Then I slowly changed,
became a better person after countless punishments by caring teachers and care
from friends. When I left the college, I had a some friends that will last for
life, some teachers who had teardrops on their cheeks as I said goodbye and
some moments that would be etched in my heart forever.</p>

<p>Then I joined the current college. I had trouble again, because again, I really
had less friends. But as years have progressed, things changed. Someone brings
you food for festivals, someone cares if you have applied for an internship,
someone plans ahead for your birthday, you fly kites, go on random trips, trust
unconditionally and share your lives with. You fall in love, you make
unbreakable friendships.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve lived most part of my life in a pseudo-family that&#8217;s not my own family. But
I never once felt not at home. It&#8217;s unexplainable how you don&#8217;t miss your own
family once you are in a society like this, but it certainly is special. Thank
you all who are a part of mine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/01/01/new-year/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-01T02:01:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/01/01/new-year</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>One year passed.</h3>

<p>I made some <a href="http://sid-rt.blogspot.in/2011_12_01_archive.html">resolutions</a> last year. I&#8217;ll quickly review them:</p>

<p>I scored some good scores, but I think the awesome winter should make
up for the bad semester. I learnt a whole lot in Python, but never a step in ruby.
I took up a worthy project. I blogged quite regularly.</p>

<p>On the other hand, I didn&#8217;t keep to a fitness regime. I didn&#8217;t build any code, probably.
And I didn&#8217;t take one single step towards that goal - learning a foreign language. French, my love!</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Ups and Downs.</h3>

<p>I had a good semester, a bad vacation. A bad semester again, then a great winter. Overall, it&#8217;s been
a fancy ride. Spent a lot of time with friends, went on awesome trips and even did some circus, but
all ended well.</p>

<h3>New friends, lost gems.</h3>

<p>Ah, winter and summer. Countless ones, it&#8217;d be bad if I failed to mention some. So I wont try at all.
But one could look at my <a href="https://facebook.com/siddhartha.thota">facebook</a> activities and easily find out who were the people.</p>

<p>Sachin, Dravid, Laxman, Ponting and many more disappear from the glorious green grounds. Atleast, with
their gloves and pads on, taking stance on the crease. Dravid finds himself comfortable in front of the
camera already.</p>

<p>I cant remember the countless other gems the world lost, either in action, or from life. I&#8217;ll try and mention
them as time goes and I miss them.</p>

<h3>Aging memories.</h3>

<p>Now NITK has become old, the fateful summer long past, a bad semester behind me, and everything seems
to be fading. I don&#8217;t want to forget how bright the other side was - trips, LNG, birthdays, etc. But one
can&#8217;t stop the tides or time.</p>

<h3>Sweet and sour moments.</h3>

<p>There are way too many, but I have the curse of forgetting (blessing in disguise). I can&#8217;t even remember
the moments, but when I remember the sweet ones, I&#8217;m elated. I also take my lessons from the sour ones.</p>

<h3>Broken promises, gritty decisions.</h3>

<p>Including the resolutions, and several others that I took on the trot.</p>

<p>Like the earth around the sun, life goes one full circle.
This time around, let&#8217;s make it better, more memorable and more beautiful.</p>

<h2>Resolutions 2013</h2>

<p>Resolutions for this year are as follows, I&#8217;ll refine them as time passes</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Finish the project taken up in Winter School.
Take it to the logical conclusion, whatever it is, and try to put my best into it.</p></li>
<li><p>Apply for the best offers I can get for the summer.
This includes CMU, Google SOC, or anything else.</p></li>
<li><p>Improve my English, learn a foreign language (French?)
This has been on the list for too long now.</p></li>
<li><p>Score a perfect 10 - whoa, that&#8217;s a little over-ambitious, but aiming at stars I&#8217;ll
atleast reach the moon.</p></li>
<li><p>Be punctual, not procrastinating and, borrowing from a blog, be proactive. I&#8217;ll
elaborate on this when I get time.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>This year is going to be the most important year of my life, and whatever turns and twists my life
will take, will be decided by this year. So I need to in the best of my form and capacity, which I
will try to do.</p>

<p>Any feedback is welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Towards the end of Winter School]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2012/12/20/its-getting-over/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2012/12/20/its-getting-over</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So days are flying. Our research is finally taking some shape.</p>

<p>I understood the algorithms and the theory behind what we are doing, now. I can
even give an &#8216;Elevator Speech&#8217; about our topic now!</p>

<p>There were a couple of &#8216;How to write a research paper&#8217; lectures.
One made me think we almost had a research paper, while the other made me think I&#8217;m an idiot! The second was a formal one
where emphasis was on the methodology, &#8216;research behind the research&#8217; and so on, which was
for serious, big papers. I couldn&#8217;t follow much of it.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Anyway, now that we have most of our code figured out, I left it for my teammates to finish it. Well,
I haven&#8217;t introduced to you both of them, Hardik Sanghvi, Madhumita Kedlaya - students of
Electronics Engineering from MS Ramai&#8217;y&#8217;ah College.</p>

<p>Food is great. MSRIT has provided some good food these days, keeping me full all the time. No, not
even the occasional snacks. Except the <em>midnight snack</em>, as always.</p>

<p>Well&#8230; I guess I&#8217;ll tell if there&#8217;s any solid result from our research - tomorrow will be
the D-Day when the code will be ready.</p>

<p>Tata!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter School 2012 (Weekend!)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2012/12/17/winter-school-2012-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T14:31:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2012/12/17/winter-school-2012-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here comes the weekend. Like a spring that lost a huge attached weight, I sprang
to my usual mode - relax, tv, roam, eat, chat.</p>

<p>The weekend actually began with the program on Friday - <em>TGIF</em>!
Bharathanatyam, porki dance, some impromptu english/hindi songs, retro hindi karaoke, and a good dinner later,
I was having the best time of this vacation. We learned that <a href="http://cs.cmu.edu/~dadamson">David Adamson</a>,Octopress
who is a grad student of CMU and one of our guides, has an office close to the inventor
of smileys - :-) - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scott_Fahlman">Scott Fahlman</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The night was spent watching random videos, and the best find was the kid <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wupr-p96i68">Jack Vedgen</a>.
Simply amazing. After being amazed, I sleep at 4AM, wake up at 11AM and realize that I was all alone.
Rest of the weekend was simply spent lazing around, roaming with friends and
sleeping. The week has taken a toll on me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2012/12/08/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T20:43:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2012/12/08/first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So. Finally I have a (sorta) final setup. And I&#8217;m not yet sure of the theme. But here I
go, this will be my place to put up thoughts, keep track of things that intrigue me, that
interest me. I often tend to forget what I want to remember.</p>

<p>So this is like a diary - a technical/personal blend - and I hope to do it regularly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
