<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: journal | the Ephemeral Me]]></title>
  <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/categories/journal/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ephemeral.me/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-16T12:26:29+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ephemeral.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[At the door to a new beginning]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/05/09/at-the-door-to-a-new-beginning/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-09T18:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/05/09/at-the-door-to-a-new-beginning</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since too many memories are clogging my mind, this is not a well thought out
piece about parting and graduating, this is just a compilation of thoughts that
came about during the last few days.</p>

<p>What began as the fruit of some hard work and extreme luck, what came after a
choice that decided the direction of my life (between medical or engineering -
that's all that's available for a middle class average student), what started
with me as a dumb, innocent and childish teenager, is now coming to an end. As
it ends, I contemplate. The several dimensions of life here have left a trove
of memories.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>First, food, yes. Food didn't come easily. We struggled to feed ourselves.
Several things saved us by providing the occasional-slowly-turned-regular
respite from the mess food.  The grand dinners in the mess, the big fat slices
of Ideals from 3rd/5th blocks, the sunday Masala Dosas, the gobi manchurians,
the kheers, the rasnas and the paneer items. The (pseudo-)veg food from GNPD,
the variety of alu paranthas from the NC, GBNC, GNPD and GPD, the lassi at
Bittus, the lingering after-taste of pani puri after a satisfying streak of
chats at Kailash, the cheap milkshakes at the cold house, the staring sulky
I'll-take-you-for-granted waiter at Suraj, the funny proprietor of SD (and NC
(and the supplier at every meeting/seminar with free food)), the teetotaller's
gang eating fried rice at RR, the (pseudo-)unlimited buffets in Mangalore, the
holy shrine called Pabbas, the weirdest remixed and still home-like food from
Ram Bhavan, the mirage called Kebab Studio, the unexplored Froth on Top. So
while the messes happily served humongous amounts of undercooked rice, the
tasteless sambar-rasams, the painfully limited good sabzis and bulletproof
rotis, awful breakfasts and extremely light evening snacks, nobody cared.</p>

<p>Travel proved to be the best drug. Treks to KP, Bandaje, numerous waterfalls
around South Canara in the obscurity of western ghats, bus trips to nearly every
tourist place, the insanely fast bike trip to Yana and the best ever beach trip
to Gokarna. The getting lost at Bandaje, the missing train in Goa, the shivering
cold of west-India and the bloody rain in KP. The unparalleled flatness of the
Rann of Kutch, the remnants in the wilderness of Dholavira and the single
majestic hill that stood in the middle of hundreds of kilometers of chest-deep
saline water. The Sawai Gandharv and the Yamini. The food at Mysore's homes, the
lovely nostalgic lazy times in Goa's home. The duo's wandering to Bekal and
wading the tides to reach Sasihitlu. The bathing in dirty backwaters at Pavanje,
the journey on the side of the engine of a goods train through rainy hills to
Doodhsagar, the exploring of Chennai and the fairs of Mangalore.  The
accompanying artists to schools and attending Conventions.  Travel was that
boost that would push us through semesters. Travel recharged our batteries as it
drained our physiques and filled us with memories.</p>

<p>Friends fill as much the NITK life as water does a watermelon. Friends will
constitute all the memories that define college life. When it is a hostel with
not a very easy life, the bond multiplies in strength. With assignments and
projects, scorching heat and incessant rains, block timings and warden whining,
bad food and no water, surprise tests and relative grading, we found several
reasons to bond. The thought of missing my friends frightens me.</p>

<p>I made all kinds of friends. The irritatingly nerdy kind, the elite sarcastic
kind, the studious kind, the shy kind, the hardworking kind, the algorithm
master kind, the silent yet scholarly kind, the chatter-y kind, the NID kind,
the half naked around the varandah kind, the artistic kind, the matching
wavelength partner-in-crime kind, the laughing rampage kind, the ladiesman kind,
the directory-of-every-girl kind, the deceitful kind, the loving kind, the idol
kind, the adventurous kind, the leader kind, the silent kind, the overly caring
kind, the rude rowdy kind, the methodic perfectionist kind and so many more.
Much to my surprise, I have realized  every one of the friendships is worth
treasuring. I will.</p>

<p>NITK has given me several things that are unique and bring a rush of feelings
every time I remember them. The beautiful beach, the unforgiving rains, the
villages around the campus, the unpredictable whether and towering lighthouse.
Taking late evening strolls to the beach, early morning excursions on the
railroad to reach Pavanje, getting on the terrace to watch the clouds build up
while the lighthouse's beam searched the edges of the horizon, passionately
shouting in TV room and breaking furniture and shouting for and against teams,
standing up with pride as India grabbed another world cup "for Sachin", the
parting of couples at 9:55, the follow-me-everywhere Snowy and the endless
headbanging nights of Incident. The thursday evenings, the precious times with
artists and the concerts by the greats.</p>

<p>The fun-filled and sometimes irritating eerie joblessness spanned our schedules
like ether, dominating everything else, causing me to sometimes doubt the
purpose of last 4 years. When I look back, I feel guilty sometimes.  The most
prominent of all guilts that plague my mind is serious: I didn't learn anything.
Yes. In the four years, 192 credits, hundreds of gruelling examinations and
assignments and project (reports), I have learnt nearly nothing. Academics was
full of compromises, last minute slog, lies, curses and incessant demands for
"research and publication". I came in to become an engineer. My curriculum
focussed on anything but that. Teachers demanded research-y projects, indented,
numbered, abstract-litreature survey-result-future work-references-ified
reports, overnight submission to conferences, copied assignments, pointless
examinations and 75% attendances. They came in to class to teach subjects in a
way that made me cringe innumerable times. We doodled, whatsapped, Gangnam
danced, dozed, ate, played and ogled in class. Labs, though, were marginally
better, where I felt I was learning. Projects started with outlandish demands
right from the beginning, and never ended. Placing a random number generator
function with a probability of 74% and claiming a 74% result hurt my confidence
more than I thought it would. (Oh and dont please get me started about corruption
and inefficient administration and equal measure of indifference among students
and administration.)</p>

<p>While the conclusion that education is secondary came right in the beginnings, I
looked around for what else I could absorb from this cauldron of talent and
diversity. It would be the greatest mistake to not learn anything after living
as one among such a diverse talented set of people. And so I did, and did well
in retrospect.</p>

<p>It's all coming to an end. Now all that lies ahead of us is a future - one
that's full of opportunities along with confusion, one that holds as many doubts
as hopes. I dont know what's in it for me, but right now I dont have many
regrets.</p>

<p>The no-due certificate that I hold in my hands now seems silly. I know I can
never pay back everything that I owe to NITK.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A CSI in Surathkal]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/02/05/a-csi-in-surathkal/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-05T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/02/05/a-csi-in-surathkal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That afternoon, we were waiting in our project guide's room for my teammate to
arrive.  He came 5 minutes late as usual but this time he had the weirdest
excuse to give. Not so much an excuse, what he said made me forget that he was
actually late - "there's a murdered body in front of the department!".</p>

<!-- more -->


<p> Shocked as I should be, I looked out of the transparent wall panes
of the front of the department. These panes line the entire length of the front
side of the building. It's a useless ornament pretty much, an exception being
the nice panoramic view that it provides of the old East Side campus.  This time
it wasn't so nice, for an ominous crowd was already gathering around a spot on
the side of the highway. Several thoughts crossed my mind
- "Could it be a student? A teacher? Natural death?  Accident on the highway?
  Animal body?". From fourth floor, nothing was clear.</p>

<p>I gave a heads up to my guide about the happenings before we sat down to discuss
the project and he replied "It's all a part of life. Come in, let us continue".
We sat down for an hour or so and when we came out, I had an overwhelming desire
to just be down there at the scene to watch the proceedings. The Wire, one of
the best TV shows of all time, has got me hooked to crime scenes and police
work. So I thought I'd catch a bite of it in real life.</p>

<p>My excitement was slightly dampened when I caught the first glimpse of the scene
- mind you, this was about an hour after the murder. There was no cordoned-off
crime scene. No vehicles with beacons (hey, the politicians need them beacons
to parade around, how can they be spared for silly crime work?). No forensic
experts sweeping for DNA and fingerprints and hair samples, no nothing. There
were a couple of police men staring at this and that, whistling at the
occasional bus that stopped at the bus-stop. There were people, both standing
around and in the buses, staring at the small patch of blood on the ground
'cordoned off' using 2 road-blocks from NITK. The most serious looking man in
the scene was the head of Watch at NITK, in his khakhi uniform.</p>

<p>I left the scene soon, because there were only photographers taking photos of
blood and people creating rumors. Before I left, I met the police guy and
asked him, "What happened?". He said, "Murder". Of course.</p>

<p>After chilling out for half an hour in the nearby Amul shop, I came by again
to see what had developed. Hey, there were a couple of police now with gloves
on. Wow, I thought, CSI! The one with the more serious uniform walked around,
searching for something. Hair? Nah, he's not getting any, other than some from
the heads of soon-balding guys like me around the crime scene. Murder weapon?
Maybe. But after an hour and half, now I thought it should be a miracle to
find anything useful in a crime scene thronged by civilians.</p>

<p>He bent down and picked up something from the gutter with his gloved hand. A
plastic cover that someone had dumped as waste. Then he came back to crime
scene, and picked up a juice carton that was crushed by a hundred footsteps.
How were they evidences, I still wondered, for they looked like all the other
garbage in our campus. Now he bent down near the blood. As I realized what he
was doing, my mind went numb. He scooped up the bloody mud with the carton,
and put it into the cover from the dump. Carefully, he filled 3 more covers
from the dump with the mud from the crime scene. Then he put them all in
another big cover that his assistant had painstakingly collected from the
dump, then hung it all on the handlebar of his white police Pulsar, took off
his gloves, drove away. CSI done.</p>

<p>Life was back on track as I hurried to SJA to set up stage for the Hindustani
Shehnai concert that was going to start in an hour. As I went about the
arrangements, a friend showed me a photo on her phone which she said was going
viral on WhatsApp. It was a close-up photo of a body lying in foetal position
on ground. His guts were spilled out, right arm cut, fingers scattered, head
bludgeoned and was clearly dead.</p>

<p><figure class="img cap-top"><img src="/images/nsfw-murder-pixelated.jpg" title="(NSFW) Photo on WhatsApp" ><figcaption class="imgcaption">(NSFW) Photo on WhatsApp</figcaption></figure></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First day at Intuit]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/14/first-day-at-intuit/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T14:22:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/14/first-day-at-intuit</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Le me dozing off in Intuit office - jobless on the first day - on my comfortable
SteelCase chair.</p>

<p>"Hey, Wake up!"</p>

<p>I'm up. It's my mentor Harsh Vardhan Gupta. He has a serious look on his face, and his phone in his hand.</p>

<p>"The team manager is back from the US. He tried to wake you up, but you wouldn't respond. He called me."</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I took a few more moments, still sleepy after the heavy lunch.</p>

<p>"He just came in. He wanted to see you, but he found you sleeping with Facebook open on your
screen. He's pissed off!"</p>

<p>I slowly realized the gravity of the situation. I just screwed up my first meeting with my team manager. I probably even screwed up my
chances with Intuit.</p>

<p>"What? Did he come in? He saw me sleeping?", I asked, rubbing my eyes.</p>

<p>"Yes, he tried to wake you up. He's off for a meeting now. He asked me to send him your phone number.", he said, and in a hurry took down my
number on his mobile.</p>

<p>"Alright, he's angry, so probably you should see him as soon as he's back!"</p>

<p>The colleagues voiced their concern, too. "Harsh, you meet
the manager first!", "Siddhartha, go apologize!", "He's not that bad either, he
might forgive you..", they said. Nothing helped the mood.</p>

<p>I washed my face. Tried to do something work-related, but was just plain worried. I
was imagining the manager, and was nervous like shit.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>.</p>

<p>Then the whole office burst out into laughter, and they come and pat my back and
apologize.</p>

<p>The manager is still in the US. Intuit doesn't care if we sleep during work,
heck, they even have a sleeping room. Intuit has begun well indeed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oh! The places you'll go]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/01/oh-the-places-youll-go/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-01T10:18:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/05/01/oh-the-places-youll-go</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a beautiful poem I found from the movie Fracture. It's written
by <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oh,_the_Places_You'll_Go!">Dr. Seuss</a>. It's inspiring!</p>

<blockquote><p>Congratulations!<br/>
Today is your day,<br/>
You're off to Great Places!<br/>
You're off and away!</p>

<p>You have brains in your head.<br/>
You have feet in your shoes.<br/>
You can steer yourself<br/>
any direction you choose.<br/>
You're on your own. And you know what you know.<br/>
And YOU are the guy who'll decide where to go.<br/>
<!-- more -->
You'll look up and down streets. Look 'em over with care.<br/>
About some you will say, "I don't choose to go there."<br/>
With your head full of brains, and your shoes full of feet,<br/>
you're too smart to go down any not-so-good street.</p>

<p>And you may not find any<br/>
you'll want to go down.<br/>
In that case, of course,<br/>
you'll head straight out of town.</p>

<p>It's opener there<br/>
in the wide open air.</p>

<p>Out there things can happen<br/>
and frequently do <br/>
to people as brainy<br/>
and footsy as you.</p>

<p>And when things start to happen,<br/>
don't worry. Don't stew.<br/>
Just go right along.<br/>
You'll start happening too.</p>

<p>OH!<br/>
THE PLACES YOU'LL GO!</p>

<p>You'll be on your way up!<br/>
You'll be seeing great sites! <br/>
You'll join the high fliers!<br/>
who soar to high heights.</p>

<p>You won't lag behind, because you'll have the speed.<br/>
You'll pass the whole gang and you'll soon take the lead.<br/>
Wherever you fly, you'll be best of the best.<br/>
Wherever you go, you will top all the rest.</p>

<p>Except when you don't.<br/>
Because, sometimes, you won't.</p>

<p>I'm sorry to says so<br/>
but, sadly, it's true<br/>
that Bang-ups<br/>
and Hang-ups<br/>
can happen to you</p>

<p>You can get all hung up<br/>
in a prickle-ly perch.<br/>
And your gang will fly on.<br/>
You'll be left in a Lurch.</p>

<p>You'll come down from the Lunch<br/>
wuth an unpleasant bump.<br/>
And the chances are, then,<br/>
that you'll be in a Slump.</p>

<p>And when you're in a Slump,<br/>
you're not in for much fun.<br/>
Un-slumping yourself <br/>
is not easily done.</p>

<p>You will come to a place where the streets are not marked.<br/>
Some windows are lighted. But mostly they're dark.<br/>
A place that could sprain both elbow and chin!<br/>
Do you dare to stay out? Do you dare to go in?<br/>
How much can you lose? How much can you win?</p>

<p>And IF you should go in,should you turn left or right...<br/>
or right-and-three-quaters? Or maybe not quite?<br/>
Or go around and back and sneak from behind?<br/>
Simple it's not, I'm afraid you will find,<br/>
for a mind-maker-upper to make up his mind.</p>

<p>You can get so confused <br/>
that you'll start in to race<br/>
down long and wiggled roads at a break-necking pace<br/>
and grind on for miles across weirdish wild space,<br/>
headed, I fear, toward a most usless place</p>

<p>The Waiting Place...</p>

<p>...for people just waiting.</p>

<p>Waiting for a train to go<br/>
or a bus to come, or a plane to go<br/>
or the mail to come, or the rain to go<br/>
or the phone to ring, or the snow to snow<br/>
or waiting around for a Yes or a No<br/>
or waiting for their hair to grow.<br/>
Everyone is just waiting.</p>

<p>Waiting for the fish to bite<br/>
or waiting for wind to fly a kite<br/>
or waiting around for Friday night<br/>
or waiting, perhaps, for their uncle Jake<br/>
or a pot to boil, or a Better Break<br/>
or a string of pearls, or a pair of pants<br/>
or a wig with curls, or Another Chance.<br/>
Everyone is just waiting.</p>

<p>NO!<br/>
That's not for you!</p>

<p>Somehow you'll escape<br/>
all that waiting and staying.<br/>
You'll find the bright places<br/>
where boom bands are playing.</p>

<p>Oh, the places you'll go! There is fun to be done!<br/>
There are points to be scored. There are games to be won.<br/>
And the magical things you can do with that ball<br/>
will make you the winning-est winner of all.<br/>
Fame! You'll be famous as famous can be,<br/>
with the whole wide world watching you win on TV.</p>

<p>Except when they don't.<br/>
Because, sometimes, they won't.</p>

<p>I'm afraid that some times<br/>
you'll play lonely games too.<br/>
Games you can't win<br/>
'cause you'll play against you.</p>

<p>All Alone!<br/>
Whether you like it or not.<br/>
Alone will be something<br/>
you'll be quite a lot.</p>

<p>And when you're alone, theres a very good chance<br/>
you'll meet things that scare you right out of your pants.<br/>
There are some, down the road between hither and yon,<br/>
that can scare you so much you won't want to go on.</p>

<p>But on you will go<br/>
though the whether be foul.<br/>
On you will go<br/>
though your enemies prowl.<br/>
On you will go<br/>
though the Hakken-Kraks howl.<br/>
Onward up many<br/>
a frightening creek,<br/>
though you arms may get sore<br/>
and your sneakers may leak.</p>

<p>On and on you will hike.<br/>
And I know you'll hike far<br/>
and face up to your problems<br/>
whatever they are.</p>

<p>You'll get mixed up of course,<br/>
as you already know.<br/>
You'll get mixed up<br/>
with many stray birds as you go.<br/>
So be sure when you step.<br/>
Step with care and great tact<br/>
and remember that Life's<br/>
a Great Balancing Act.<br/>
Just never forget to be dexterous and deft.<br/>
And never mix up your right foot with you left.</p>

<p>And will you succeed?<br/>
Yes! You will indeed!<br/>
(98 and 3/4 percent garanteed!)</p>

<p>KID YOU'LL MOVE MOUNTAINS!</p>

<p>So...<br/>
be your name Buxbaum or Bixby or Bray<br/>
or Mordecai Ali Van Alenn O'Shea<br/>
you're off to Great Places!<br/>
Today is your day!<br/>
Your mountain is waiting.<br/>
So... get on your way!</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[on parting]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/04/30/on-parting/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T13:25:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/04/30/on-parting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's not often that you end up with a circle of friends that become a part of
you. You wont know it until it's time to bid adieu, as with all other things.
But once you realize it, you hope that, you know, time stops. Just one more
outing, one more trek, one more day of fun. Until that inevitable separation
comes.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>It's only getting worse as we are growing older, and world is getting smaller.
By separating I don't mean that we are no longer going to the same school but
living in the same town, as it was with our childhood friends. This time, we
came from far off places, and we are going even further. Chances are, we are not
going to meet for a long time.</p>

<p>Is it going to matter? I told myself that we are going to find new friends,
visit new places and hang out with new circles until one day, soon enough, we'd
stop missing the old <em>junta</em>. It's only the fear now, but it'll be better in
future, I assured myself. "Hey, it's nice to change, who knows, it might all be
for good.. Chill.. ", I assured Raja who was apprehensive about the same
thing.</p>

<p>One thing is for sure. Times are not going to be as sweet as they were during
the past couple of years. Neither are we going to be adolescent and in college
again, or are we going to have a company as fine as this. Come what may, nothing
can parallel the world we shared, the moments we spent laughing, eating or
strolling together. The <em>pani-puri</em> will carry the memories with each bite, as
will every outing in future.</p>

<p>That dream, of coming together some day, going on a trip to Europe and
participating in <em>La Tomatino</em> like in one of those movies is already forming.
Hell, even a proposal of buying a custom-made bus and roaming the country is already
being proposed by Raja. It should sound easy, take  a weekend off, meet up and have fun.
How difficult can it be to do that? Future remains to be seen.</p>

<blockquote><p>Ya'll will go away, <br/>
some across seas, <br/>
some to universities, <br/>
and some to work, <br/>
but away it is.</p>

<p>There's no end to hoping this would never end.<br/>
On the road ahead, see you around the bend!</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
