<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: story | the Ephemeral Me]]></title>
  <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/categories/story/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ephemeral.me/"/>
  <updated>2016-08-16T09:05:42+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://ephemeral.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A CSI in Surathkal]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/02/05/a-csi-in-surathkal/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-05T05:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2014/02/05/a-csi-in-surathkal</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That afternoon, we were waiting in our project guide's room for my teammate to
arrive.  He came 5 minutes late as usual but this time he had the weirdest
excuse to give. Not so much an excuse, what he said made me forget that he was
actually late - "there's a murdered body in front of the department!".</p>

<!-- more -->


<p> Shocked as I should be, I looked out of the transparent wall panes
of the front of the department. These panes line the entire length of the front
side of the building. It's a useless ornament pretty much, an exception being
the nice panoramic view that it provides of the old East Side campus.  This time
it wasn't so nice, for an ominous crowd was already gathering around a spot on
the side of the highway. Several thoughts crossed my mind
- "Could it be a student? A teacher? Natural death?  Accident on the highway?
  Animal body?". From fourth floor, nothing was clear.</p>

<p>I gave a heads up to my guide about the happenings before we sat down to discuss
the project and he replied "It's all a part of life. Come in, let us continue".
We sat down for an hour or so and when we came out, I had an overwhelming desire
to just be down there at the scene to watch the proceedings. The Wire, one of
the best TV shows of all time, has got me hooked to crime scenes and police
work. So I thought I'd catch a bite of it in real life.</p>

<p>My excitement was slightly dampened when I caught the first glimpse of the scene
- mind you, this was about an hour after the murder. There was no cordoned-off
crime scene. No vehicles with beacons (hey, the politicians need them beacons
to parade around, how can they be spared for silly crime work?). No forensic
experts sweeping for DNA and fingerprints and hair samples, no nothing. There
were a couple of police men staring at this and that, whistling at the
occasional bus that stopped at the bus-stop. There were people, both standing
around and in the buses, staring at the small patch of blood on the ground
'cordoned off' using 2 road-blocks from NITK. The most serious looking man in
the scene was the head of Watch at NITK, in his khakhi uniform.</p>

<p>I left the scene soon, because there were only photographers taking photos of
blood and people creating rumors. Before I left, I met the police guy and
asked him, "What happened?". He said, "Murder". Of course.</p>

<p>After chilling out for half an hour in the nearby Amul shop, I came by again
to see what had developed. Hey, there were a couple of police now with gloves
on. Wow, I thought, CSI! The one with the more serious uniform walked around,
searching for something. Hair? Nah, he's not getting any, other than some from
the heads of soon-balding guys like me around the crime scene. Murder weapon?
Maybe. But after an hour and half, now I thought it should be a miracle to
find anything useful in a crime scene thronged by civilians.</p>

<p>He bent down and picked up something from the gutter with his gloved hand. A
plastic cover that someone had dumped as waste. Then he came back to crime
scene, and picked up a juice carton that was crushed by a hundred footsteps.
How were they evidences, I still wondered, for they looked like all the other
garbage in our campus. Now he bent down near the blood. As I realized what he
was doing, my mind went numb. He scooped up the bloody mud with the carton,
and put it into the cover from the dump. Carefully, he filled 3 more covers
from the dump with the mud from the crime scene. Then he put them all in
another big cover that his assistant had painstakingly collected from the
dump, then hung it all on the handlebar of his white police Pulsar, took off
his gloves, drove away. CSI done.</p>

<p>Life was back on track as I hurried to SJA to set up stage for the Hindustani
Shehnai concert that was going to start in an hour. As I went about the
arrangements, a friend showed me a photo on her phone which she said was going
viral on WhatsApp. It was a close-up photo of a body lying in foetal position
on ground. His guts were spilled out, right arm cut, fingers scattered, head
bludgeoned and was clearly dead.</p>

<p><figure class="img cap-top"><img src="/images/nsfw-murder-pixelated.jpg" title="(NSFW) Photo on WhatsApp" ><figcaption class="imgcaption">(NSFW) Photo on WhatsApp</figcaption></figure></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[404]]></title>
    <link href="http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/03/18/story-1/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-18T11:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://ephemeral.me/blog/2013/03/18/story-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Riding the college roads on his cycle, passing by couples savouring the sweet
evening air, he couldn't help his mind while it raced back to the past,
screeching to stop a few years back. The memories were refreshing, just like the
cold wind rushing on the hot summer night as he pedalled happily on the downward
slope of the deserted road. He let himself recount those memories again, as
he let the bike take a decelerating climb and come to stop by itself. The
memories of the terminated relationship came flooding in.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>It was years since he started liking her. Though he never expressed his feelings
explicitly, they were close to each other, either fighting or working together.
He didn't know who asked out who, but it turned into their first date. He was
excited as he waited for the bus to stop at the bus-stop where she'd be waiting.
Heart pounding, he stared out of the window.</p>

<p>There she was, unmistakably glowing in the middle of the crowd. Waiting there,
twirling her silken hair between her fingers. His heart jolted as he got up from
his seat, made it to the door of the full bus. Squeezing himself out of the
door, he saw her standing there, a shy smile on her face as her elder sister
stood by her.</p>

<p>He fumbled for words, and a warm smile from the sister was the best thing on his
list of expected things to happen. He was relieved when she thrust a 500 note
into his pocket, asked them to have fun and left. After all, they were still 17
and he knew he could accept that from her sister.</p>

<p>Then he looked at her. As beautiful as she already was, she looked gorgeous in
the attire like nothing he had never seen any real girl wear. A sleeveless blue
top with a wide strap over the shoulder, accentuating her curves perfectly, was
complemented by dark knee-long pants. A vanity bag - he didn't remember the
details - she hung on her shoulders. Hair dark, long and smooth as he always new
her. Managing to shake off the feeling of awe, he asked her, <em>"Which way?"</em>.</p>

<p>On the way, he didn't know what to think, he couldn't imagine how to spend the
rest of the day with her. <em>"Shall I go to a normal restaurant? Will she think
I'm too cheap?" "No, she knows me better, so I'll go to a normal restaurant
only" "I dont have much money to go to a big restaurant anyway"</em> and so on, the
debates inside his head went on.</p>

<p>As he walked, he wanted to hold her hand, just like it happened in the movies.
Their hands only brushed, despite his best efforts to 'accidentally' touch them,
hoping they'd turn into holds. He couldn't muster up enough courage to go ahead
and actually hold her hand. <em>"I'll try after the movie"</em>, he told himself.</p>

<p>They finally got hold of their seats. Middle, front-ish maybe, he doesn't
remember. They sit down, making small talk as the credits rolled. As the movie
started, they started eating popcorn. The big bucket in the armrest between them
was the only one they had, and every time her hand touched his, it was like an
electric shock running through his arm. He could feel her smooth skin through
his shirt. He hoped they'd hold hands, but she never did.</p>

<p>He felt a sudden jerk as the cycle passed pretty fast over the hump on the road,
and the jolt brought him back to the reality. To this day, he never stopped
seeing her in his head, whenever he felt lonely. It was like he never stopped
loving her, and whatever happened that caused their separation was
subconsciously erased from his head. He didn't remember one conversation of the
period. It was as if he was lying on the sofa at home all the three months, and
suddenly she was not his friend anymore. He couldn't remember what happened.</p>

<p>He pulled up near the footpath, put his cycle on stand and sat down nearby.
Taking out his mobile, he pondered over the thought of whether or not to message
her. It was awkward now, after having ended the whole thing rather harshly. She
would not message or call, and whenever he did, it didn't last long.
Ignoring his better judgement, he messaged her.</p>

<p><em>"Hey"</em></p>

<p><em>"Heya, long time!"</em></p>

<p><em>"Remembered you, so messaged!"</em></p>

<p><em>"Nice! wasap?"</em></p>

<p>The conversations were much better then, hindi written with english and full of
love. Now they were simply <em>"howdy"</em> and a couple more lines.</p>

<p><em>"Do you remember the day we went to watch that movie?"</em></p>

<p><em>"Yes, I bet you dont know a bit about the story"</em>, she said, rightly.</p>

<p><em>"Yes, I dont know :P, but dont blame me"</em></p>

<p><em>"Why? Your memory sucks, but still..."</em></p>

<p><em>"That you looked so hot didn't help anyway"</em></p>

<p><em>"Hot? What was so special about me anyway"</em>, she mockingly asked. I was the one
who always told her she was pretty, and she never believed it.</p>

<p><em>"That dress you wore - I'd never seen anything like that before"</em>, every bit of
it being true.</p>

<p><em>"That was nothing special"</em>, well if that wasn't special, what has she started
wearing now, he wondered.</p>

<p><em>"That sleeveless - I loved the way it showed off your curves!"</em>, once again
with the fear that she might stop chatting already. She went on.</p>

<p><em>"Sleeveless? I've never worn one whenever we went out!"</em>, she said.</p>

<p><em>"The sky blue one?"</em>, I remembered perfectly, how could she not?</p>

<p><em>"I don't remember wearing any such dress whenever we went out! I'm sorry!"</em>,
her reply was surprising. Never? He so clearly could see her, he thought.</p>

<p><em>"Well, what did you wear then, then?"</em>, he asked, confident that she would
remember it now.</p>

<p><em>"A white half-sleeve t-shirt with brown strips!"</em>, swish came the reply.</p>

<p>How was that possible? He could not be wrong! <em>"Then the blue sleeveless?"</em>, he
now realized he didn't even know what to call that top. It was like one of those
vests guys wore.</p>

<p><em>"Haha, no. I dont have any sleeveless of that color! And anyway, why would I
wear something like that for that outing?"</em></p>

<p><em>"Because it was a date? :P"</em></p>

<p><em>"A date? Silly! Haha! We had that whole bunch of friends with us, too! What
date are you talking about?"</em></p>

<p>He didn't know what to reply.</p>

<p>Before he could analyze what he just learned, he noticed that the cycle tyres
were flat. To his surprise, there were two long slashes on the tyre. How did he
drive all the way? He remembered riding till there. The cool wind, the
pleasurable ride. So crystal clear.</p>

<p><strong>FOOTNOTE1:</strong> <em>Saar,</em> search title in google if you are not a web developer. <br/>
<strong>FOOTNOTE2:</strong> Inspired by someone's true story. Modified to dramatize.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
